<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS407-001 UA Fall 2016</title>
    <description>A website for notes and study materials for CS407 offered at  The University of Alabama during Fall 2016.
</description>
    <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 10:30:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 10:30:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 8 - Day 2 (Chapter 9)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quizlet.com/_2lwqvy&quot;&gt;Quizlet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position:fixed;bottom:1em;right:1em; background:black;padding:.5em&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h2 style=&quot;margin:0;color:white&quot;&gt;Navigate using audio&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;player&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  new AudioNavigator({videoId:&quot;kxlnRyGpG2s&quot;});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio 0:00:40.105677&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;part-c-of-project&quot;&gt;Part C of Project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit it October 12th at midnight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By October 13, before class, we need everything prepared.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Have to come to class with lo-fi prototype&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:06:31.739881&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;when-would-you-use-voice-recognition&quot;&gt;When would you use voice recognition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;beneficial&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;poor&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;driving / hands occupied&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;when you’re in public&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;easy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;when the search is complicated&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;no mouse / keyboard&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;names&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3xIO7Luhaps&quot;&gt;Is voice recognition replacing typing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:20:24.722999&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;obstacles-of-speech-recognition&quot;&gt;Obstacles of Speech recognition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:21:54.759599&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noisy environments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Poor quality microphone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Different accents and dialects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn commands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;error correction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;obstacles-of-speech-production&quot;&gt;Obstacles of Speech Production&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:23:59.605676&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;privacy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pace of speech&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pronunciation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;short-lived&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:28:52.281136&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NaturallySpeaking video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3vuWirlt7Rw&quot;&gt;Nuance Dragon Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;speech-synthesis-types&quot;&gt;Speech Synthesis Types&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:34:41.814216&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;format synthesis&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;concatenated synthesis&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;canned&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;screen reader&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Morgan Freeman Birmingham Airport&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:42:48.061467
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IOw4kVrymFs&quot;&gt;Stanford experiment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;when-is-command-language-faster-than-gui&quot;&gt;When is command language faster than GUI?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For expert users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complicated data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:50:38.424237&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vocab&quot;&gt;vocab&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;term&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;definition&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;good scenarios for voice assistants&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;driving, hands occupied, the voice command is simple, entertainment, poor lighting&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;bad scenarios for voice assistants&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;when you’re in public, when it’s noisy, the search is complicated, you need to give it names&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;obstacles of speech recognition&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;noisy environments, poor quality microphones, accents, dialects, learning commands, error correction&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;obstacles to speech production&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;privacy, pace of speech, pronunciation, short-lived&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;format synthesis&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;speech generated using algorithms&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;concatenated synthesis&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;created using speech fragments (pasted together)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;canned speech&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;speech that has been pre-recorded&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;when is command language better than a GUI?&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;For expert users, programming, or inputting complicated data&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/10/06/week-8-day-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/10/06/week-8-day-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ch 9 - Discussion</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider voice-activated digital assistants such as Siri, Cortana or Google Talk. Identify a situation or scenario where you chose to use this personal assistant, and identify a scenario where you chose to avoid it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would find Siri, Cortana, and Google Talk useful when my hands are tied or when the alternative input is not effective (like touch screen typing). However, I would not want to use these tools when I am in a noisy area or when I have a keyboard and mouse in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a follow-on to the previous question, produce a thoughtful argument about what role spoken interaction should have in user interfaces. Be sure to list at least three benefits and limitations of spoken interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoken interaction is effective when the user has visual or motor impairments because they can interact with their device without looking at it or touching it. It is also useful for people who need to use their hands to drive a car or have their hands full. Furthermore, it is useful when the user is fatigued and wants to use an input method that is more natural and takes less thought. However, spoken interaction is hard to use in a noisy environment. It can also lead to anger when it misunderstands the user. Furthermore, it can be slower than typed input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some designers suggest that speech recognition should be used in a telephone menu system. This would allow users to interact with the system by speaking instead of pressing buttons on the dial pad. Give two arguments for and two arguments against the proposal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A speech recognition menu would allow users to not have to type complicated information. Also it would allow them to input information without having to look at their phone and potentially miss spoken information. However, if the speech recognition software fails to accurately interpret speech then the user could become  distressed and reduce the quality of the call or accidentally give the system incorrect information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define when “speech production” is successful and discuss methods for its implementation. Cite examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speech production is successful when the users understand it and interact with it naturally such as when using the Subway and receiving instructional information over intercom or when taking a tour with a robot tour guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There exist applications of human language understanding technology. Name some examples.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;List several situations when command languages can be attractive for users.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to my previous responses, command languages are most attractive when using your hands is impossible or inconvenient. Also, it is effective when users are motor or vision impaired. It is also attractive when it functions naturally so that the user feels they are simply talking to a person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/10/05/ch-9-discussion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/10/05/ch-9-discussion.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 8 - Day 1 (Chapter 8 - Fluid Navigation)</title>
        <description>&lt;div style=&quot;position:fixed;bottom:1em;right:1em; background:black;padding:.5em&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h2 style=&quot;margin:0;color:white&quot;&gt;Navigate using audio&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;player&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  new AudioNavigator({videoId:&quot;E0Fh3LN1k1g&quot;});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;websites&quot;&gt;Websites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:01:25.679338&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cool features don’t make your app easier to use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When do you apply certain features
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Simpler is sometimes better&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;examples-when-filling-in-forms-and-using-menus-is-easier-than-direct-manipulation&quot;&gt;Examples when filling in forms and using menus is easier than direct-manipulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:02:31.320854&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you have a lot of specific kinds of data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Searching is better with an input box&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you need high precision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-we-allow-users-to-select-things&quot;&gt;How can we allow users to select things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:05:05.312498&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Binary menus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Radio buttons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check boxes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sliders
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Range of input&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull-down menus / combo-box&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;palettes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ribbons
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Allows for context specific actions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shortcuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gestures
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;size of screen matters&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;considerations-for-smaller-screens&quot;&gt;Considerations for smaller screens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:13:13.823219&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Entry
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t make things too small&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Easier to overload the user&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Font size&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Layout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interruptions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;User can get a text or a call in the middle of working through a form&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Need to save state&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:23:28.918312
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0sU2Vv7twmc&quot;&gt;Apple Watch navigation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;webby-awards&quot;&gt;Webby Awards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:27:48.651847&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webbyawards.com/winners/2016/&quot;&gt;See website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hilariously hard to navigate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audio-menus&quot;&gt;Audio Menus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:51:29.693806&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can’t have to many submenus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not visible
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You don’t know if your option is even there&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;filling-out-forms&quot;&gt;Filling out forms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:55:43.507105&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you fill out a field incorrectly, it might highlight it
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Does it happen immediately or after submit, etc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E-mail for closure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modal vs non-modal forms
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;modal won’t let you do anything until you’ve interacted with it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vocab&quot;&gt;Vocab&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Term&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Definition&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;inputs for selecting&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;binary menus, radio buttons, check boxes, trees, pull-down menus, palettes, ribbons, shortcuts, gestures&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;when filling in forms might be easier than direct-manipulation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;when there is a lot of data or when you need high precision&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;considerations for smaller screens&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;data entry, font size, layout, interruptions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/10/04/week-8-day-1-chapter-8-fluid-navigation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/10/04/week-8-day-1-chapter-8-fluid-navigation.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ch 8 Discussion Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A telephone-based menu system is being designed for a magazine subscription service system. There are seven magazines available: National Geographic, Travel and Leisure, Entrepreneur, Time, Golf, US News and World Report, and Fortune. Describe three reasonable orderings of the voice menus and justify each.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reasonable ordering would be to order them alphabetically: Entrepreneur, Fortune, Golf, Leisure, National Geographic, Time, Travel and Leisure, and US News and World Report. Alphabetic ordering is preferable because the user is aware of it and can predict how long it will take to get to their desired magazine. Another reasonable ordering would be to order the magazines by popularity. This way, the user is more likely to hear the magazine they like first. Another reasonable ordering would be to order the listings by price. Therefore, special or lower prices are listed first to get the caller to be more likely to make a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide three examples of an application where menu selection and form fill-in are more appropriate than a direct-manipulation strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Form fill in is always more appropriate when filling in personal information such as name or social security because of the sensitivity and the lack of an analogy that mimics the input. Also, when choosing information from a small organized list, it is always easier to select that information from a menu. Furthermore, it is more appropriate when screen real-estate is small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design a touch screen music jukebox, which allows the user to select from a menu of the five most popular songs of the week. Draw a sketch of this interface for each of the following menu types: Binary Menu, Multiple-Item menu, Check boxes, Pull-down Menus. Argue which design serves the user best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(See attached)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are in charge of designing a menu tree for navigating 1,250 books in a digital library. Present an argument of whether the menu should have larger depth (number of levels) or breadth (number of items per level).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tree should have larger breadth so that the list is broken up as much as possible. For example, the books should be split up by genre in the first level, then another sub category in the second to make it much easier to sort through the lowest level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frequent menu users can become annoyed if they must make several menu selections to complete a simple task. Suggest two ways you can refine the menu approach to accommodate expert or frequent users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to refine the menu approach is to provide hotkeys for frequently accessed menu items. Another way would be to allow advanced users to customize a quick access bar to allow them to quickly access a more frequently used item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When users are navigating through a menu structure, they may become disoriented. The authors suggest techniques to help alleviate this disorientation such as indicating the current position in the menu. Draw a sketch of how you can show users their position for an on-line car showroom, assuming the user has browsed with the following path:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main Menu -&amp;gt; Mid-size Cars -&amp;gt; Honda -&amp;gt; Accord&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(See attached)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are some design considerations for fluid navigation of small-screen displays, e.g. Smartphone or even smart watch screens?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is less screen space to show the amount you have navigated so it is better to give the user a gestural navigation approach to let them swipe in and out of levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Critique the design of the dialog box below in the text. This dialog box is used to alert clinicians who try to prescribe the drug Warfarin, because it increases the risk of bleeding in patients already on Aspirin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem I have with the buttons is that the buttons do not easily describe what they do. I think the buttons should say “Keep Only Asprin” or “Keep Only Warfarin” to make it as obvious as possible what you are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/10/03/ch-8-discussion-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/10/03/ch-8-discussion-questions.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 6 - Day 2</title>
        <description>&lt;div style=&quot;position:fixed;bottom:1em;right:1em; background:black;padding:.5em&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h2 style=&quot;margin:0;color:white&quot;&gt;Navigate using audio&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;player&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  new AudioNavigator({videoId:&quot;fCQfB7D_gYU&quot;});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quizlet.com/_2jhip3&quot;&gt;Quizlet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio 0:00:51.868280&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ch-7&quot;&gt;Ch 7&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feelings that result from good interfaces
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ease in learning&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sense of mastery&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;enjoyment&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;competency&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;retention&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;eager to show others&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;desire to explore the interface&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:04:16.445987&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does this relate to eight golden rules?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:06:08.520121&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Eight golden rules
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;strive for consistency&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;universal usability&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;informative feedback&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;closure&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;reduce errors&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;easy reversal&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;user in control&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;reduce short term memory&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Shared
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;All of the feelings generated by good interface are things that map back to the eight golden rules&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:08:18.173476&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;direct-manipulation&quot;&gt;Direct manipulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:11:37.896001&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;easy to learn
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;natural&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;proper feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rapid use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;metaphor should prevent errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;examples&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:12:41.234016&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desktop
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;matches what you see on an actual desk&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Maps
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;touch the map and it moves like a globe&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;translational distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;problems&quot;&gt;Problems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:15:47.581942&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;overcomplicating&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;implementation difficulties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual clutter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;small margin of error&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;not as universally usable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;zooming and such might prevent you from seeing other features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-examples&quot;&gt;More examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;video games&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CAD tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kiosks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Touch screens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS in general&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:21:09.614770&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-1&quot;&gt;Video 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1UtlOgkOGy4&quot;&gt;Desktop metaphor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:22:47.725187&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;part of building interfaces is doing things that map to what people already do because it’s easier to learn
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s a tradeoff&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;airline-company-discussion-question&quot;&gt;Airline Company Discussion Question&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“An airline company is designing a new on-line reservation system. They want to add some direct-manipulation features. For example, they would like customers to click a map to specify the departure cities and the destinations, and to click on the calendar to indicate their schedules. From your point of view, list four benefits and four problems of the new idea compared with their old system, which required the customer to do the job by typing text.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Audio 0:27:49.156075&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;benefits&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;problems&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Encourage people to explore the places they might want to go&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;having too much information might prevent the users from seeing things like special offers and such&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;A user might know where they’re going on the map, but not know the name of the place they’re going&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;A user might not know where they’re going on the map, but know the name of the place they’re going.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Reduce the formatting you have to do in order to check the date and location input&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;You can show users prices at the same time that they pick out their location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;d-and-3d-interfaces&quot;&gt;2D and 3D Interfaces&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:30:08.766829&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Considerations for which interface makes the most sense
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What are you trying to represent?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Time and money resources
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;3D takes more time&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How much information the user wants to see&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;d-execution&quot;&gt;3D Execution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The desktop is technically 3D
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Things are behind each-other, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:32:11.659850&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t distract people with too much eye-candy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep manipulation of objects straight-forward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;teleoperation--telepresence&quot;&gt;Teleoperation / Telepresence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medical field
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Avatar doctor&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:35:20.389707&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Teleconference&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Skype&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-2&quot;&gt;Video 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:36:28.113523&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;augmented-reality&quot;&gt;Augmented Reality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vb79-_hGLkc&quot;&gt;Robo doctor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Examples
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pokemon go&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Google glass&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;10 yard line in football&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:46:39.190090&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vocab&quot;&gt;Vocab&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Term&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Definition&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;positive feelings from good interfaces&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ease in learning, sense of mastery, enjoyment, competency, retention, desire to show others, desire to explore features&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;direct manipulation principle 1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;continuous representations of the objects and actions of interest with meaningful visual metaphors&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;direct manipulation principle 2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;physical actions or presses of labeled buttons, instead of complex syntax&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;direct manipulation principle 3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;rapid, incremental, reversible actions whose effects on the objects of interest are visible immediately&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;translational distance&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;a measure of how good the metaphor of a direct manipulation system is&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;problems of direct manipulation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;overcomplicating, implementation difficulty, clutter, not as universally usable&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3D best practices&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;don’t distract users and keep manipulation of objects straight-forward&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;teleoperation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;controlling something remotely&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;teleoperation use cases&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;drones, medical field, business conferences&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/22/week-6-day-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/22/week-6-day-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discussion - Ch 7</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Describe three principles of direct manipulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first principle of direct manipulation is, “continuous representations of the objects and actions of interest with meaningful visual metaphors.” This means that while interacting with the system, there should always be visual feedback that coincides with what you are trying to accomplish with the interface. The second is, “physical actions or presses of labeled buttons, instead of complex syntax.” This means that instead of giving the user a language or another tool for communication with the system, the system should have an interface that reflects real-life controls, such as physical buttons or actions. The third is, “rapid, incremental, reversible actions whose effects on the objects of interest are visible immediately.” This means that changes should occur in real-time, but be undoable in order to give the user maximum control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give four benefits of direct manipulation. Also list four problems of direct manipulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One benefit of direct manipulation is that it reflects the real world so users should, ideally, already know how to interact with it. Another benefit is that direct manipulation systems make you feel more in control because they respond faster. Furthermore, direct manipulation systems also try to take advantage of as many of your senses as possible so that you feel more connected to it. One more benefit is that user satisfaction increases because the user feels more in control of the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem of direct manipulation is that sometimes it leads to overcomplicating the system. For example, sometimes text is the most efficient interface to interact with. Also, direct manipulation systems generally consume all of the user’s focus so that they cannot use multiple programs at once. Furthermore, sometimes the visual representations used by the system are not intuitive, so users have to learn them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Examining the success of video games can provide insight for interface designers. Explain what lessons can be learned by videogames for interface design, but also provide examples of areas where it is ineffective to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Videogames have mastered the art of using 3D worlds as an interface. Therefore, it would be beneficial to look at videogames as an example of good 3D representations.
  However, videogames are entertainment programs and not practical devices, so they are not as good models for how to make a practical system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An airline company is designing a new on-line reservation system. They want to add some direct-manipulation features. For example, they would like customers to click a map to specify the departure cities and the destinations, and to click on the calendar to indicate their schedules. From your point of view, list four benefits and four problems of the new idea compared with their old system, which required the customer to do the job by typing text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four advantages of the map and calendar is that 1. Many users might find it more intuitive to navigate the interface this way. 2. Some users might not know the name of the airport they need to go to, so they can see all airports in the region they want to travel to and then click it. 3. The calendar could help them precisely choose the date and time they would like to travel. 4. The calendar could help prevent them from mis-scheduling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four disadvantages are 1. It would in some cases be faster to select the correct airport from a list. 2. It would be faster in some case to manually type in the time and date you’d like to travel. 3. It might be harder to find the correct airport from a map. 4. People might choose the wrong time and date from a calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List a few guidelines for an effective 3D interface:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An effective 3D interface has instant feedback, logical representations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List an example of teleoperation or virtual reality. Consider what a future application (that does not presently exist) might do. Be creative!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/22/discussion-ch-7.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/22/discussion-ch-7.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 6 - Day 1</title>
        <description>&lt;div style=&quot;position:fixed;bottom:1em;right:1em; background:black;padding:.5em&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h2 style=&quot;margin:0;color:white&quot;&gt;Navigate using audio&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;player&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  new AudioNavigator({videoId:&quot;baRqCbe8icI&quot;});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Error messages are always bad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What design rule have we learned which should prevent vague error messages?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:00:57.791883&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Prevent errors instead of displaying them&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-case-studies&quot;&gt;Three Case Studies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ATM case study&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:02:23.040821
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What jumped out at you?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Iterative design&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:04:29.375915&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You have to think about non-obvious use cases such as poor lighting&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Video taping responses to the system&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Eye-tracker
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;You get to see where the user’s attention is at all times
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;You could see if there’s something distracting&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;You can see how long it takes for people to hone in on what they’re looking for&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Do the users look at the screen when they should look at the keypad (vice versa)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Other improvements
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;use-case testing
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;security issues&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;line formed&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:09:08.048261&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;video-discussion&quot;&gt;Video discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:17:05.371007&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very rapid design &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=szr0ezLyQHY&quot;&gt;Nordstrom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agile development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very iterative design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-design-question&quot;&gt;Apple design question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:20:23.461046&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What guidelines make sense and which are less clear?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/ios/human-interface-guidelines/&quot;&gt;apple guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;table&gt;
          &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
              &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;makes sense&lt;/th&gt;
              &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;don’t make sense&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
          &lt;/thead&gt;
          &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
              &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;clarity&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;deference&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
              &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;consistency&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;user control&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
          &lt;/tbody&gt;
        &lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:30:08.254667&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-driven-design&quot;&gt;Data-driven Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:32:15.672038&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teradata.com/Resources/Videos/Volvo-Cars-Fueling-innovation-with-Data-Analytics-and-the-Internet-of-Things/?LangType=1033&amp;amp;LangSelect=true&quot;&gt;volvo video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:41:34.442311&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volvo takes advantage of big data to better design cars
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Part failure statistics&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;User customization choices&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;cars interconnected&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vocab&quot;&gt;Vocab&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Term&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Definition&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iterative design&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;design based on the most recent version of the design where changes and refinements are made&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;big data&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;using large data sets to make business decisions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/20/week-6-day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/20/week-6-day-1.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ch 6 - Discussion Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Consider additional requirements and technology to further complicate your analysis of an Automated Teller Machine (ATM) design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use eye-tracker data to further analyze the product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Eye-tracker data could show us where users look first when they use the interface which would allow us to better place the key features they are looking for in the places they look first
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider accessibility (universal usability) issues such as lighting, physical placement of ATM, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;The ATM should be placed on ground level (not raised or lowered) so that users do not have to crane their posture up or down to interact with it. Also it should be in a well-lit environment so that users can correctly see the interface they are using. Furthermore the ATM should be placed in its own space, away from other things people want to use so that users are not crammed into a space and so that, if a queue of users forms to use it, they do not block the paths of others.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider user profile issues, e.g. is this the first time a user is using an ATM?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Perhaps to help new users, if more than a couple of user errors occur, the interface should begin to display non-intrusive help messages to guide them towards their goal.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requirement to perform beta and/or market tests?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Positioning and lighting of the environment of the ATM could be tested in control groups to find the most preferred setup of the ATM by users.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there other stress factors such as a looming time deadline or a personal safety issue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;One stress factor users might encounter is if they are using the ATM while a large queue has formed behind them or if they have waited a long time to use the ATM. The frustration of waiting a long time and the stress of wanting to use the ATM quickly so others can use the machine will cause the users to make more mistakes and have less pleasant experiences.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review the iOS Human Interface Guidelines in the iOS Developer Library at: https://developer.apple.com/ios/human-interface-guidelines/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) select one guideline that makes perfect sense and seems easy to incorporate into a design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;In my opinion, clarity is the most logical of the guidelines. It is straight-forward to have a guideline which asks the developer to make things easier to read, see, and interact with.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) select another guideline that is much less clear requiring further explanation or analysis to incorporate into a design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;The deference guideline sounds much more abstract and harder to implement. For example, it asks the developer to make subjective improvements to the interface such as being &quot;beautiful&quot; and &quot;easy to understand.&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present, the drive to use Big Data to define or enhance corporate strategies seems to be a global business trend. State an example of where this data can improve a business, focusing on user interface aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One could examine big data such as user click positions, eye-tracking data, and so on from mass repositories and try to find trending key points where people look and click in order to find better places to position elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cite a past experience where user interface development methods might apply to another system development activity that might not have a strong user interface component.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/20/ch-6-discussion-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/20/ch-6-discussion-questions.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 5 - Day 2</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quizlet.com/_2j11i3&quot;&gt;Quizlet on terms from this lecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position:fixed;bottom:1em;right:1em; background:black;padding:.5em&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h2 style=&quot;margin:0;color:white&quot;&gt;Navigate using audio&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;player&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
  new AudioNavigator({videoId:&quot;S48TwgvMW08&quot;});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;announcements&quot;&gt;Announcements&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presentations review
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Feedback on the homework
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Makes you pay attention to things you already do&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Gives you better tools to critique the interfaces you use&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:02:01.342658&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did it change the way you might design an interface
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Yeah, knowing eight golden rules, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experienced designers know that they don’t have all the answers
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You need user input&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:05:23.445473&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have to think about non-standard situations
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;unpredictable usage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expert-reviews-and-heuristics&quot;&gt;Expert Reviews and Heuristics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kinds of reviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;guideline review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;heuristic review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:08:30.995883&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cognitive walkthrough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;formal usability inspection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exercise&quot;&gt;Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google slides&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advising appointment interface&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usatoday.com/&quot;&gt;news site&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Intuitive to find the news I was looking for&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Inconsistent size of layout elements&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Advertisements auto-play and scroll with the page&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:22:56.056939&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have to be aware of competition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;think-aloud&quot;&gt;Think-aloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:39:47.500776&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talking through an interface task as it is performed
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Could potentially distract the user from completing the task&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;not necessarily natural&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;gives a better insight into how the user approaches the interface&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:43:40.208723&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-prototype&quot;&gt;Paper-prototype&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:44:48.676886&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People aren’t as hesitant to request changes to it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Faster to build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;survey-instruments&quot;&gt;Survey Instruments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio 0:48:28.430657&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what are things you need to think about when designing a survey?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Having good representative users&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t bias your questions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;acceptance-tests&quot;&gt;Acceptance tests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can’t have subjective requirements
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can’t be “easy to use”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Has to&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vocab&quot;&gt;Vocab&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Term&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Definition&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;heuristic evaluation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;expert review where an interface is checked for conformance with a short list of design heuristics (such as the Eight Golden Rules)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;guideline review&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;expert review where interface is checked for conformance with the organizational or other guideline documents&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;consistency inspection&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;expert review which checks if the interface has fonts, color schemes, layout, etc. compared to other common interfaces&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;formal usability inspection&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;expert review styled like a courtroom meeting in which the interface is presented to discuss its merits or weaknesses&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;cognitive walkthrough&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;expert review in which the expert simulates walking through the interface and performing typical tasks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;sight tracking&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;method for observing how users progress through an interface and what catches their attention&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;think-aloud&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;talking out loud while a user performs a task to understand their thought-process&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;bad requirement&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;A subjective requirement such as “needs to be easy to use”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/15/week-5-day-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/15/week-5-day-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chapter 5 Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Describe at least three different types of expert review methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heuristic evaluation is where experts review an interface and decide whether or not it conforms to well-established rules, such as the Eight Golden Rules. Guidelines review is where the interface is reviewed in order to see if it conforms to the guidelines established by the organization. Consistency inspection is when the interface is compared to other interfaces in order to check for consistent fonts, formats, schemes, and other details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare and contrast controlled psychological experiments and usability tests in the evaluation process of user interfaces. Be sure to include the benefits and limitations of each.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a psychological experiment, the method of testing the interface is more empirical: one gathers evidence for or against the usability of the interface through surveys and other techniques. However, it is harder to use psychological experiments because you have to find very specific things about the interface to test and a sample of users who match the demographic of users who will see the interface. In a usability test, however, the tests are more subjective. One can ask the user, “Did you enjoy using the interface,” for example. However, usability tests are less empirical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give two reasons why expert reviews are useful. Also give two limitations of expert reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expert reviews are useful because usability experts are trained to know exactly what to look for in an interface and how to find it quickly to make sure it is high quality. One limitation of expert reviews is that the expert might not fully understand the scope of the project and might not give advice geared towards the actual desired functionality. Also, the expert might not be familiar with the user group who is intended to use the product and might make suggestions which are irrelevant to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions 5-7, refer to the following instructions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One argument against the current interface design of a popular word processor is that it has all the functional menu items appearing together which cause the interface to be too complex. This complexity results in a confusing and frustrating experience for novice users. An alternative design is to provide different levels of functional complexity, so users can choose the level that is suitable for them, then advance to higher level as they get familiar with the tool, thus feel more comfortable and learn more efficiently. You are asked to conduct usability testing to compare these two designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which type of usability testing should be used for this situation? Explain why.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competitive usability testing should be use to compare the new version of the interface which allows you to move up to higher levels of complexity to the old interface which does not. This would allow for a good side-by-side comparison of the usability of each version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List some general principles of subject selection in usability testing. How should you select subjects for this case?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would make sense to pick a group of familiar users and a group of unfamiliar users and find how they feel about hiding parts of the interface. One reason for this is that the advanced users might be unhappy that the features they like to use are hidden. Also, it is important to see if the unfamiliar users wish that they could see some of the more advanced features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List and briefly describe the steps in the usability testing you would conduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would create a survey of possible problems or benefits the users might find and ask them to rate how they believe the product stacks up. For example, if they thought there was not enough buttons on the page, there would be a spot for them to mark that they were dissatisfied with the number of buttons on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/15/chapter-5-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jmbeach.github.io/CS407-001/2016/09/15/chapter-5-questions.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
